Okay,
this transcript, we're going to try to kill two birds with one stone,
Claude, and I want to work on the
Setmaster case study. And then I also want
to have Claude,
as a creative director, use this transcript to
design a new page,
which is Thank you us.
a landing page showing off Setmaster 3.
And so, I'm going to first just talk about the
history of Setmaster, the problem that it solves,
and the evolution from that. And I'm through prototype through web
app. And I'm going to talk about using Claude.
And I'm going to talk about just everything,
stream of consciousness. And,
uhm, Claude,
you're going to plan out the case
study as an outline from this transcript.
You're not going to write the whole case study yet.
We're going to iterate on an outline first.
And then, in parallel,
as a creative director, you're going to design the landing page
for Setmaster 3. Drawing from any of the content in this transcript,
as well as the Setmaster 3 repository.
Okay, so the history of the Setmaster is,
I'm a pro DJ,
and I have a huge catalogue of 100,000 tracks,
and of them, I usually maintain a catalogue of around
10,000. And I also perform with other DJ partners,
and so some of their catalogue is on my machine as well.
Uhm, and when I got to be
producing more and more sets, sets for performance,
uh, I found that utilizing just Traktor
or just Rekordbox for set preparation was super slow.
Since I'm a data engineer,
I kept envisioning ways that I could see automating,
uhm, the tedious part of preparing for a set.
And the tedious part is like searching through and filtering and sorting this
huge catalog and also comparing against recent and past sets.
So you don't replay the same track too many times for your
listeners, uhm, which is,
uh, an important part of being a pro DJ,
always being fresh, uhm,
another part that I was constantly doing was comparing Spotify
playlists that I maintain on the go with the Traktor playlists
of stuff I actually own, things I have actually brought into my Traktor collection.
Now, in a modern way, If you pay for a subscription,
then you And it's not about owning the track,
you have access to huge libraries,
but it is still about organizing those,
so really there's even more friction now that you have
an even bigger library if you bring streaming into this.
So, uhm, I wanted to create an intuitive
set preparation spreadsheet with all of the spreadsheet handiness,
like copy-paste and move things around and have,
uhm, big white space between chunks,
uhm, Uhm, you know, allow,
uh, a more freeform palette while
developing a DJ set.
Because that's the reality of developing a set,
is tracks move around earlier and later in the set.
Uhm, at the end of you buy more sets,
you're adding things in, you're replacing.
And you wanna keep detailed notes,
so when you come back to work on the set,
you remember where you left off, remember things you liked and didn't like,
and remember cue points. Uhm,
so, I wanted to create a tool
in Excel, uhm, actually the first iteration was Google Sheets,
because I wanted just cross-device backup,
ah, to be built in, uhm,
and so, home. In the Google Sheet, in the Excel version,
I just wanted one line to be a transition,
instead of, like, in Tractor or Recordbox,
you're reading from top to bottom, uhm,
and so, even if you put in comments in that program,
it's hard to read, it takes up too much real estate,
it didn't make any interest, and intuitive sense, so,
I wanted a two-column idea,
with the track you're coming from,
in the left side, the track you're going into,
in the right, and to me,
that was way more intuitive as a professional DJ,
to read a whole transition from top and from left to right,
that's really what you're working on in a DJ set,
is specifically the transition, uhm,
the set list can just be a list of tracks,
and you can move that around, done and done, but what you really need
to focus on, in a transition on the cue points,
and cues to yourself on volume,
and, uh,
tempo changes and things like that, uhm,
and so that's the impetus for the set preparation function
inside of Setmaster. And that's And then what I did is I just started
using it. I was DJing all the time,
and on planes creating DJ sets,
and it just became a multi-tab beast of a workbook,
which was super helpful for, uhm,
creating sets and sharing them across the my devices,
and, uh, having a scratchpad that just made sets
go faster. And then while using it I kept having ideas for features,
and so that, uhm,
evolved into Setmaster 2, which was exclusively an extension of a VBA
and Python backend,
uhm, where I started importing the collection from Tractor so I could do
data science filtering, to,
uhm, have multi-filters against key,
BPM, could quickly switch between. search artists,
and I used this not in a live situation,
but during set prep, and just kept taking minutes and minutes away from,
uhm, the tedious part of,
of set preparation and, and catalog management,
and then I created a one-off workbook flow to take output
from the Python in Setmaster 2 and,
uh, import exportify.net,
uhm, CSVs of the Spotify playlists
and then compare those to and that's really when the lightbulb got
bright in my head, I thought I had something powerful there to,
uhm, you know, really make the comparison of what I've been listening to out
and really want to buy and quickly filter down to which tracks those are.
Go online and buy them and next thing I know they're into my sets,
uhm, that saved hours every month,
uhm, and I gotta call out Lexicon in this study
too because Lexicon has a comparison tool.
It's really powerful. It didn't handle,
like, the bulk listing filtering that I wanted,
but I still love what Lexicon does and this isn't supposed to compete with
it. It's just like another functional,
uh, application of,
of filtering metadata and stuff.
And so, the prototype I used for, like, a year and just kept adding
little formatting buttons and little things that were helpful during set preparation and
that eventually became sort of a performance tool.
Performance view ability as well,
so during DJ sets, I could see,
like, more real estate and a zoomed-in version of my set prep
list with all its cues and different color coding in it.
It's just awesome for long DJ sets that have maybe some,
uh, complicated transitions that have been rehearsed and I,
I just need to look, glance, at Setmaster and my memory of that
specific transition comes up, uhm.
And so then, when I started becoming a Cloud Architect,
uhm, last year,
in, in early 2025,
I thought, oh, I really need to turn this into a,
a web application. And I really didn't get time to try to start
doing that until this year, and so I started the web
app version of Satmaster, which I call Satmaster 3,
in, uhm,
in early July. And gave Claude,
uhm, the,
the prototype and all the VBA, and we worked on the planning documents for,
for several days, uhm,
in parallel to other work, and then,
uhm, created, uhm, uh,
the web app version, which then I've been using Claude to iterate on,
uh, over the last week, and,
and also I've been out DJing, so I've been using the web app and
testing it in a live situation, and I've now done four rounds of
fine-tuning, uhm,
and, and, uh, one big round of bug fixes after the initial build.
There's a ton of documentation, and now we have a,
uh, public mirror of the repository that's programmatically made
by two, uh, Setmaster 3 private repository.
So, there's a downloadable and launchable,
uh, version of the program for the public to start to use.
And, uh,
that's, you know, case study.
For the case study, I really want to,
uh, stress that this tool is,
takes out the tedious catalog filtering part so you can connect your
brain's idea with the tracks you have that fit that idea faster.
And leaving more time for DJing and more time for music discovery,
uhm, and this,
this tool has taken hours,
put hours back into DJing, uh,
and taken hours out of catalog filtering and comparing Spotify contents
versus Traktor, so it's really a, a,
a tedious time saver is like what Setmaster does.
And then the other thing it does is the,
the set preparation, uhm,
is just unparalleled as far as making set prep fun.
And more interactive,
you're not fighting with Traktor or Rekordbox filtering.
It's your, your new source of truth,
your own customizable emoji palette,
uhm, your own, uhm,
way of, of workflow, and the best mix timer so you know how long
sections are and how long your whole mix is.
Uhm, and another element that has always been in the back of
my mind is this is a great tool to teach new DJs how to
DJ, uhm, not really beginner but,
uhm, intermediate. Once they understand transitions and song composition
a little bit, you can, uh,
really teach them how to cue a song and then,
uhm, structurally line up key,
line up BPM, line up different cue points,
uhm. Uh, this setmaster,
you know, the setpages on the setmaster will be a great teaching tool,
uhm,
to, uh, for a student to learn how to make a more complex
transition or grouping of transitions.
Uhm,
the other thing to put in the case study is this is always meant
to be part of my Anthropic Portfolio.
Uh, this will be a work in progress.
I plan to add record box functionality
so you can import files. You can your record box collection,
uhm, instead of Tractor.
Uh, I don't have a timeline on that,
but it's definitely going to be in a future version.
Uhm,
and, yeah,
I think that's it. That's good, so I'm going to,
now the, thinking about the landing page,
uhm,
you know, you can, the audience of the case study is people
who want to hire me, but the audience of the landing page,
uh, is people primarily that,
but secondarily,
users, or advanced users,
or techie users, uhm,
so the landing page isn't like for beginners.
It's supposed to be impression, impressive as well.
So, join bra, highlights from the deeper case study
material, uhm, while keeping the landing page more of like a hype
page with the history just being interesting.
On the landing page, I want it to be. Uh,
more like if Native Instruments owned Setmaster 3
and had a landing page for it, uhm,
and they were showing its origin story and its awesome functionality.
So design that page like that. And you'll want to have placeholders
for me to put videos for me showing the app,
and different parts of the app, and placeholders for nifty screenshots
of the app in action as well. Uhm.
And that landing page will also feature a link to the public
GitHub repository where people can download it.
Uhm, it'd be awesome if that could even be a one-click button
to download straight from the page.
There should be two buttons, one to go to the public repo in a
new tab and another one just to download,
uh, in one click. But I guess they'll have to choose Windows or Mac,
uh, and which Mac to download.
So take that into consideration from here. From the landing page,
uhm, the other thing we want from the landing page
would be to book an intro call with me and also
a, uh, link to the main website.
Okay, that's it for this transcript.
I'm going to work with Claude on it now.